HAO WANG (Howie)

+434-227-8996 · howiewang2020@gmail.com · @howiework · howiework.com

PROFILE

Experienced web designer and developer with well-honed design and development skills gained through an interdisciplinary background in architecture, graphic, and web. Professional experience using design tools, and adept at solving real-world problems through design thinking, research, analytical, and communication skills.

KEY COMPETENCIES

UIUX / Agile / TestingReactFigma / CanvaJavaScript (ES6)NodeJS / ExpressAdobe Creative Suite (PS, ID, IA)HTML 5 / CSSPython / ChatGPT / AIBilingual in Chinese and English

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

University of Virginia Comprehensive Cancer Center

Feb 2023 - Present

Multimedia Creative Professional II

- Promoted to Multimedia Creative Professional II from contract web developer.
- Lead UVA Cancer Center website enhancement for better aesthetics, functionality, and devices responsiveness.
- Create engaging digital content like banners and infographics, employing innovative designs.
- Collaborate with UVACCC stakeholders to align design with organizational goals.
- Use user-centric design with usability testing and feedback for enhanced digital experiences. Manage project timelines and priorities efficiently.

Codingheroes.io Feb 2024 - Present

Newsletter Editor (Udemy instructor Jonas)

Manage popular monthly web developer newsletter for Jonas, a top Udemy instructor, using email marketing and content creation to yield 86k subscribers and remarkable 40% open rate.

3Advance Dec 2022 - Jun 2023

Web Developer (contract)

- Build web development project Boaturu Admin & Renter sites with latest front end technology, e.g. React, Next.js, Css-in-JS, Radix UI, Tailwind.
- Design web project for AARP, EC Hub 2.0 Time Entry module. Communicate closely with team and client for RFP and integrate into latest new feature design with the help of Figma & InVision.

Rawle Murdy Associates Inc (BGRM)

Apr 2022 - Jul 2022

Web Developer (contract)

Work with web team to develop and enhance websites with complex integrations, APIs, animations, and functionality.

Sunwater Institute Mar 2022 - Apr 2022

Web Developer (contract)

Work on migrating source code for an institute platform product, coordinating with an overseas team and closely collaborating with local design and research teams.

CERTIFICATIONS

FrontendExpert Certificate

AlgoExpert

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Udemy Certifications *List link

- Next.js & React: Complete Guide
- Node.js, Express, MongoDB Complete Bootcamp 2021
- Responsive Web Design

EDUCATION

University of Virginia

Dec 2017 | Charlottesville, VA Master of Architecture

University of Mining and Technology

Jul 2015 | Xuzhou, China Bachelor of Architecture

SELECTED PROJECTS

Snap App | Photo-sharing platform

video demo; process; code

Lunch Break | Blog site

demo; code

NMAAHC | UIUX / Branding

A mobile app (UIUX focused) for a

museum

Howiework | Portfolio

Personal portfolio website using React